QUEEN OF TEARS
《淚之女王》
EPISODE 1
（第 1 集）
Everyone said it was the wedding of the century.
大家都說這是世紀婚禮
The heiress to Korea's most powerful conglomerate
韓國最大集團的繼承人
married a new recruit.
居然與新進員工結婚
It's been three years already,
已經三年了
but it seems like only yesterday.
但彷如昨日
People ask me how it feels to become a part
有人問我進入富豪家的心情如何？
of a conglomerate
與女王結婚生活在一起
and live with a queen.
感覺如何？
I'm not sure.
這個嘛
Would you believe me if I said this?
我這麼說，大家會相信嗎？
I'm just
我就只是
a lucky man
遇見愛的女人
who married
與她生活在一起的
the love of my life.
幸運男人
I know that people gossiped about
我知道有很多閒言閒語
how Baek Hyun-woo married me
說白賢祐與我結婚
solely because of my family
是因為我是富豪
and our wealth.
他是為了錢跟我結婚
Those rumors only began because I chose not to reveal my face
由於眾多考量，我沒有公開長相
for various reasons.
所以那種傳聞才甚囂塵上
I guess this will put an end to those rumors
我想從今天起，那種傳聞就會消失了
since I'm finally revealing my face.
因為我公開了我的長相
Our married life
我們的夫妻生活
is nothing out of the ordinary.
我想與大家都差不多
I wake up next to her.
早晨與她一同醒來
We have breakfast together.
一起吃飯
We go to work together as well.
當然我們也一起上班
How does it feel
你問我從早到晚
to be together all day and night?
都在一起的感覺如何嗎？
It makes me happy.
我每天都覺得很幸福
I'm sure some of you already know.
我想有些人已經知道
After returning from my studies abroad five years ago,
我在五年前從國外留學回來
I joined Queens Department Store, which my father owned at the time,
進入當時我父親擔任代表的 女王百貨公司
as an intern.
當實習生
You could say I was working undercover.
可以說是種臥底吧
Women know these things.
我們女生不是都能感覺到嗎？
"I see."
“喔
"This guy likes me."
這個男生喜歡我
"That's why he's flirting with me."
所以他才會暗示我”
No.
不是
That wasn't the case.
不是那麼一回事
She kept kicking the photocopier.
她老是用腳踢影印機
-So I was worried. -What's wrong?
-所以我很擔心 -怎麼了？
About the photocopier.
擔心影印機
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
But after helping her a few times,
不過我幫過她幾次之後
I started worrying about her.
我開始擔心起她了
When sending a fax…
傳真的時候…
At the time, people were gossiping about how obnoxious
當時公司裡議論紛紛
the new intern was.
說來了個差勁的實習生
So I was sure she'd get fired soon.
我心想她肯定很快就會被開除
You need to stop, Ms. Hong.
洪海仁小姐，你這樣怎麼行呢？
I've done my fair share of part-time jobs.
我打過很多工，我很了解
You're going to get yourself fired.
你這樣很快就會被開除
I don't care.
被開除也無所謂
Right. You'll just find another job.
你當然無所謂，可以去別的地方
you'll get fired there too. Do you want to bet on it?
你去別的地方又會被開除 要來打賭嗎？
You know what?
你知道嗎？
My heart jumps every time your superior scolds you.
每次你被部長罵的時候 我都會心驚膽跳
You get scolded every single day.
你到底一天要被罵幾次？
Why does it jump?
為什麼心驚膽跳？
-What? -Why does your heart jump
-什麼？ -我問你為何要心驚膽跳？
when I'm the one who's getting scolded?
是我被罵耶
Why?
你為什麼要怕？
Take your time
你好好想一想
and think about that.
為什麼會這樣吧
You can come right now.
請你現在過來
Don't you have an umbrella?
你沒有雨傘嗎？
No, I don't but…
喔，我是沒有
Take mine.
這個給你用
You always need help, and…
你老是什麼都沒有，讓我…
it bothers me.
放心不下
What is this?
什麼啊？
I made your heart jump, and now I bother you?
我老是讓你心驚膽跳 現在還讓你操心啦
Ms. Hong.
洪海仁小姐
Listen carefully.
你聽好我說的話
I didn't tell you this in case it'd make you feel uncomfortable.
一直以來，我怕你覺得有壓力 所以我都沒說
But you know,
其實
I went to Seoul National University.
我是首爾大學畢業的
And law school at that.
而且是法律系
My parents live down south,
雖然我家不在首爾
but the community respects our family.
但是在那個村裡是有名望的家庭
For example, we own over 30 cows.
舉例來說，我們家的牛超過30頭
Another calf was born a couple of days ago,
前兩天又有小牛出生
so we have almost 35 now.
現在接近35頭了
As for my studio apartment,
現在我住的商務公寓
I signed a two-year lease
也不是月租房
instead of paying monthly rent.
而是全租房
It just means I have a good chunk of money on the side.
意思是我有一筆資產
What are you getting at?
你是想說什麼？
Even if
即使
you get fired and can't find a new job,
你被開除，找不到新工作
I can take care of you.
我也可以養你
That's what I mean.
我就是這個意思
I'll be honest. I've always wanted my future wife to work.
老實說，我比較傾向雙薪家庭
But if it's you,
但如果是你
I can try being the sole breadwinner.
我願意一個人賺錢養家
I mean, don't feel pressured.
你不要覺得有壓力
It's just that
只是因為
I like you.
我喜歡你
So…
所以…
what do you say?
你覺得我如何？
You don't have to answer me today.
你可以不用今天回答我
Don't get wet.
不要淋雨
-I-- -I'm okay.
-可是… -我沒關係
Take it.
你拿去用
-Mr. Baek-- -I'm really okay.
-白賢祐先生 -我不用
But I--
我…
a driver.
有司機
Hilarious, right?
不覺得很好笑嗎？
It really is.
真的很好笑
Anyway,
總之
he's been a romantic ever since.
從那時起，他就是個 無可救藥的浪漫男子
That's how our love story began.
我們的戀愛就是這麼展開
But he was shocked after finding out who my family was.
但是當他知道我是誰的女兒之後 大受打擊
He handed in his resignation letter
他就辭職
and ghosted me.
然後搞失蹤
So…
所以…
Baek Hyun-woo, come out.
白賢祐，出來
Are you going to leave me standing here?
你要把我晾在這裡嗎？
She looked like an angel sent from heaven.
那時她真的像是女神或是天使降臨
-That's how she looked back then. -But not anymore?
-那時她看起來就像那樣 -意思是現在不是了嗎？
Of course, she's still an angel.
不是，她現在也是一樣
I told you many times
我說過好幾次了
that…
我…
I'm happy.
很幸福
Well…
嗯…
She and I
我們…
have a happy married life.
真的過得很幸福
We're still very much in love.
不論當時或現在 我們相愛的心都是一樣的
Baek Hyun-woo is getting a divorce.
白賢祐說要離婚
Seriously?
真的嗎？
-It's a secret. -Of course. We're colleagues after all.
-這是機密 -當然，我們都是同學還要擔心嗎？
Anyway, he'd like one of us to represent him.
總之他希望我們其中一個 可以當他的訴訟代理人
Yes, of course.
對啊，當然得這麼做
You're the number-one divorce attorney in this country.
韓國第一的離婚專門律師
You should do it, Yang-gi.
陽基，你來就行了
I'd…
我…
love to help him. Really.
真的很想幫他
But I'm already juggling so many cases.
可是我太多案子了，難以負擔
All right then.
來
Attorney Choi Cheol-seung boasts a 90% win rate.
我們勝訴率九成的崔哲勝律師
Can you help him?
你幫幫他吧
I'll secretly help you out.
我在幕後偷偷幫助你
Why secretly? Do it openly.
為什麼要偷偷？你公開啊
Afraid of getting on Queens' bad side
你怕被女王集團給盯上
and losing your job, you sly scumbag?
丟掉工作嗎？你這個偷雞摸狗的傢伙
That's right.
對，沒錯
You're right. That's why.
就是這樣，所以我才不要
I'd be crazy to take that job.
我瘋了才會接這個案子
Hyun-woo's aunt-in-law got divorced three times.
賢祐他老婆的姑姑離婚三次
You all know the fates of her ex-husbands' attorneys.
你們都知道他先生那邊的律師 下場是怎麼樣
They were all fired.
他們全都在這個圈子混不下去
Hyun-woo made a mistake. Why would he put us in a pickle like this?
對啊，賢祐不應該這樣 為何要拜託我們這種事？讓我們為難
-Exactly. -Let's be honest.
-就是說啊 -老實說
He was the smartest one out of us. Always the top of our classes.
賢祐是我們之中成績最好的 第一名入學，第一名畢業
So why can't he just be
他的離婚訴訟
-his own divorce attorney? -Right.
-自己來不就好了？ -對啊
-That'd be better. -I bet he'll excel.
-這樣應該比較好 -他應該會做得很好
By the way, why does he want a divorce?
不過他到底為何要離婚？
Exactly. He's living the dream life of all Korean men.
對啊，他那神賜般的好命 可是讓全韓國男人都羨慕
His wife is Hong Hae-in, the heiress of Queens Group.
老婆是女王集團之女洪海仁耶
So why?
到底為什麼要離婚？
She's a lunatic.
他老婆是瘋子
A lunatic?
瘋子啊？
Right. About that One Trillion Club group chat…
對了，社長，關於一兆俱樂部群組…
Yes. Why haven't they invited me?
對，為什麼他們不邀請我？
Our sales are only at 880 billion won so--
畢竟我們的總銷售額 目前只有8800億韓元
That's not a big gap.
又沒差多少
-We're only about 100 billion won short. -I know.
-只差一千億韓元而已 -就是說啊
I asked them to just round it up
我說還不是差不多 四捨五入就是一兆韓元
and be more flexible.
要他們有彈性一點
But it was still a hard no.
但是他們說不行
Why are they so fussy?
還真是嚴格
By the way, I heard
可是啊，社長
that Royal Department Store is bragging about how their CEO
皇家百貨公司的人老是在吹噓
will join the One Trillion Club by the end of the year.
他們家社長到年底 就可以加入一兆俱樂部
They're also boasting that they're going to set up Hercyna
而且他們還到處張揚說 海勒齊納會進駐
on the first floor next to the fountain.
他們百貨一樓的噴水池廣場旁
They must be insane.
他們瘋啦
Tell me about it. Department stores in Korea
就是說啊，韓國的百貨公司
are divided into those that have Hercyna and those that don't.
區分為兩種 有海勒齊納和沒有海勒齊納
And Hercyna only wants to work with those who are in that club.
而海勒齊納只進駐有加入 一兆俱樂部的百貨公司
It's about time
所以說
we cut off all the brands
到了該把阻礙銷售額的害蟲
that hinder our sales.
全都掃地出門的時候了
This is our periodical evaluation chart.
這是本次的定期評價表，下方整理出
we have a list of brands in the bottom 20% of sales.
銷售額排名在後20%的賣場
How many of them can we shut down?
這之中可以撤掉幾家？
Those underlined in red were in the bottom 20%
劃紅線的是有兩次以上
at least twice.
排名在後20%的賣場
In principle, they should be shut down. However…
依照原則是必須撤櫃的對象，可是…
"However"?
可是？
Why is there a "however"?
為什麼會有“可是”？
We should shut them down if we can.
可以要他們撤就要撤啊
And they said no.
他們說不行
Who said that?
是誰說的？
Director Baek Hyun-woo.
白賢祐理事
Mr. Yu, please wrap up the contract after confirming
劉組長，再次確認手續費的部分後
the commission fee.
把合約完成
Yes, sir. Also…
好，還有
The second-floor manager submitted a report.
二樓的樓管委託了一個案子
One of our customers fell and injured herself
有位顧客穿了12公分的高跟鞋
while walking in 12 cm heels.
在百貨公司跌倒受傷
Sir, the CEO would like to see you.
白理事，社長找你
I'm in the middle of a meeting.
沒看到我在開會嗎？
Well…
那個…
She wants to see you immediately. She's very upset.
社長要你立刻過去，她十分生氣
Mr. Baek.
白賢祐理事
Why can't we shut down brands that aren't profitable?
要求該撤櫃的對象撤出 有什麼問題嗎？
Many of the brands invested 500 million in equipment.
首先有幾處櫃位已經 投資了約五億韓元的設備費
We can't just kick them out.
因此無法隨便要他們走
File an eviction suit then.
提出遷讓房屋訴訟
It's impossible to win.
勝訴的可能性很低
The law has been revised many times to prevent large distributors
為了改善大型流通業者欺壓進駐業者
from abusing their power.
已多次修法
Are you saying
你是說
that I'm on a power trip?
我在
Is that it?
仗勢欺人嗎？
-That's not what I-- -Is this a nonprofit organization?
-我不是這個意思 -百貨公司是非營利團體嗎？
Are we volunteers?
我們都是在做愛心嗎？
Is it right to let them be when we're not getting
給他們昂貴的櫃位 連本錢都撈不回來
our money's worth for those expensive spots?
卻放任他們不管是對的嗎？
The sales division has deliberately excluded
業務部一直以來都刻意 將業績不佳的品牌
brands with low performance scores
排除於顧客邀請活動
from customer-invitation events and discounts to hinder additional sales.
以及折扣支援之外 讓他們無法有額外銷量
Those brands could complain to the media or sue us.
受害的賣場可以向媒體爆料
I believe a more favorable solution would be to help
我認為協助促進提高銷量
improve their sales.
會比較有利
Mr. Baek.
白賢祐理事
Did I ask for your advice?
你認為我是在問你的意見嗎？
I am telling you to shut them down.
我說要他們撤櫃
If they don't listen, file a lawsuit and win.
他們不走就告他們，然後打贏官司
I believe that's your team's job.
我想這就是法務組該做的事
Yes, ma'am.
我明白了
This meeting's over.
會議結束
Are you eager to let others know that we don't get along?
你就這麼拼命想讓別人知道 我們感情不好嗎？
Our relationship has nothing to do with this.
我們的感情跟工作是兩回事
I see.
喔
Is that why you warned the store manager that I wanted to fire
由於你這麼公私分明
about the violations beforehand to help him stay afloat?
違約條款，幫助他們生存嗎？
That manager has been with us since the beginning.
那個店家從我們百貨公司開業以來 就一直跟著我們
And he's still just as hardworking.
現在也無比認真在工作
Fine. You're awfully kind and caring to others.
好吧，對別人非常溫暖 有情有義又細膩的白賢祐先生
Do you want to be a hero or something?
你是想當英雄嗎？
Quit playing the martyr and treat those close to you better.
別做那種無謂的事 對你身邊的人好一點
Those close to me?
我身邊的人？
As in you?
是你嗎？
What?
什麼？
Do you really think
我們是彼此
we're close?
身邊的人嗎？
I need to talk to you.
我有話要跟你說
Come to the lounge in an hour.
我一小時後在休息室等你
Fine.
隨便你
DIVORCE SETTLEMENT AGREEMENT
（離婚協議書）
ARE YOU ON YOUR WAY? I'M HERE.
（你過來了嗎？我到了）
WHERE ARE YOU? FORGET IT. I'M LEAVING.
（你在哪？算了，我走了）
Come to the family room.
到家族室來
DIVORCE SETTLEMENT AGREEMENT
（離婚協議書）
What took you so long?
你怎麼這麼晚來？
I texted him late.
我很晚才叫他
You don't need to remind him.
要叫他才會來嗎？
He knows we have a family meeting.
不知道這個時間就要過來嗎？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
What kind of interview was it?
你說要做什麼採訪？
It was the culture section of Hanyang Economic Daily.
那是《漢陽經濟》的文化專欄
It's a heartwarming interview where CEOs and politicians
是關於執行長和政治人物
show their houses and families.
介紹家人和房子的採訪
They were both interviewed.
兩位要一起接受採訪
Why show the house? They're not celebrities.
有必要公開房子嗎？他們又不是藝人
We had to do something about the tabloids.
那你要任由謠言 在證券界亂傳不管嗎？
I agree. People gossiped about how they were separated last year.
沒錯，上個月就傳出兩人分居
It's all because they see you arguing at work.
還不是因為你們倆老是在公司吵架 才會有那種傳言
-You argued? -Yes, today.
-你們吵架了？ -對，今天
It wasn't a simple argument.
已經超越吵架的程度，會議室裡的人
Right, Hyun-woo. About the Fair Trade Commission…
對了，姐夫 上次說的公平交易委員會的事
They keep calling us in for trivial matters.
他們老是為一些小事找我們過去
Could you take care of that?
請你解決一下
You should ask the Legal Team of Queens Mart.
那是屬於女王超市法務組的業務
They're just too dense.
我們的人理解力很差
But you're quick-thinking and smart.
但是姐夫一點就通，處理事情又聰明
And the higher-ups at the Fair Trade Commission love you.
公平交易委員會的長輩們也都喜歡你
We have our own jurisdictions--
我們各有各的管轄範圍…
Why can't you just say you'll do it?
要你做就做，怎麼話那麼多？
And you two.
還有你們兩個
I want you to have a baby.
生孩子
People need to stop gossiping.
不能再讓人當成八卦的話題
Have you contacted Dr. Joo?
有跟朱醫師說好了嗎？
Yes, I booked an appointment.
有，我已經預約了
She'll get the prenatal checkup,
做完產前檢查之後
then begin the procedure right away.
馬上進行施術
As for Hyun-woo, after the baby is born,
孩子出生之後，白女婿
you'll go to Boston
依照原定計畫在明年和後年
within the next two years to get an MBA.
到波士頓攻讀MBA
I told you this already.
上次我說過了
I'm not interested in getting a degree.
我不打算再取得學位
And I also said
我不也說過嗎？
that it wasn't up to you.
那不是由你來決定
They don't owe us a grandkid, so stop pressuring him.
唉唷，他又沒欠我們，別再逼他了
Drink your tea, Hyun-woo.
喝茶吧，白女婿
But you see,
不過
I'd prefer to meet Su-bin in May.
既然要見秀彬，我希望是在明年五月
Who is Su-bin?
誰是秀彬？
Who do you think? It's my future granddaughter.
還會是誰？就是我即將出生的外孫女
Her name means "remarkably shining."
優秀的秀，文質彬彬的彬
Not bad, right? Hong Su-bin.
這個名字不錯吧？洪秀彬
I see.
喔
Will she be Hong Su-bin
她不是叫白秀彬
instead of Baek Su-bin?
而是洪秀彬嗎？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Do you not want her to have her mom's surname?
你不喜歡她從母姓嗎？
We don't need to follow the patriarchal system.
戶主制都已經廢除了
I think it's quite old-fashioned to use the father's surname.
並且我認為只能從父姓非常迂腐
But when I asked you about giving Geon-u his mom's surname,
可是爸，上次我問你說 我們家建宇從母姓好不好
you said it was nonsense.
你卻要我廢話少說
This is different.
這兩件事一樣嗎？
Isn't it the same? No?
不是一樣嗎？不一樣嗎？
We need to talk.
我們談談
We're having a baby despite everything that's going on?
這種情況下，我們還要生孩子？
And I'll be going abroad alone?
接著我要自己出國？
What's the matter?
怎樣？
Isn't that a good thing?
自己去不是很好嗎？
Don't tell me you want me to come.
你不會是想要我一起去吧？
Of course not.
怎麼可能？
Exactly.
對啊
Then do your part and go abroad.
那你就乖乖照做，要你去留學就去
We'll have others raise our baby anyway.
孩子自會有別人幫忙養
It's convenient and nice. What's the issue?
有什麼問題？不是又方便又好嗎？
"Nice"?
好？
Are you happy about this?
你覺得這樣好嗎？
Seriously?
真的嗎？
Do you really want a baby?
你想跟我有孩子嗎？
If it's needed.
如果需要的話
Yes?
嗯
Did you tell them I'd like to sign off before they publish the article?
你有跟他們說報導登出前 要先經由我們核准吧？
Of course.
那是當然
Also…
還有
Tell them to introduce Director Baek properly.
白賢祐理事的介紹要寫正確
Don't forget to mention that he studied law at SNU.
不要漏掉他是首爾大學法律系畢業的
What?
怎樣？
Stop doing these interviews. I'm done with them.
不要接這種採訪 我不要再做這種事了
Do them alone if you must.
你想做自己去做
How can I when they're about married couples?
這是夫妻專訪 我怎麼有辦法自己做？
You can tell them all about me.
你自己一個人講，講我是怎樣的丈夫
Tell them how we're so in love
講我們有多麼相愛，愛得死去活來
and happily married.
有多麼幸福到不行
Tell them everything.
全都告訴他們
It's all a lie anyway.
反正全都是謊言
Hey.
嗯
I want the photos first.
要他們先把照片傳過來
I'll pick the one they'll use.
我要親自挑選刊登的照片
Why do they publish useless articles?
為什麼都只有沒用的新聞？
Why didn't they mention
為什麼我上次
how I anonymously donated 200 million won?
匿名捐款兩億韓元都沒有報出來？
Look.
不是啊
I know I did it anonymously
我是匿名捐款
because I didn't want anyone to know, but everyone should know.
極度不想要讓別人知道 但是要讓眾人皆知啊
Isn't that what the PR Team is for?
這不就是公關室的作用嗎？
I'm so frustrated.
我真是覺得鬱悶耶
What was that for?
幹嘛打我？
What?
怎樣？
What do you want?
你要做什麼？
What is it?
幹嘛？
Tell me from there.
不要過來，在那邊說
Use your words.
用講的啦
Gosh.
唉唷
-Soo-cheol. -What?
秀哲
Don't avoid me.
不要躲
Or you'll get
免得你
a black eye and start bawling again.
又被打得鼻青臉腫在那邊哭
Wait--
不要
Are you crazy?
你瘋啦？
Why are you hitting me?
為什麼要打我？
Is Hyun-woo your friend or someone younger than you?
白賢祐是你朋友還弟弟嗎？
"Quick-thinking"?
什麼一點就通？
How dare you?
你好大的膽子
Disrespect my husband again,
你再敢對我老公放肆
and I'll kill you.
你就死定了
-Answer me. -Fine. I get it.
-還不回答？ -我知道了，知道了啦
That crazy witch.
那個瘋婆子
Why get mad at me when she bullies Hyun-woo all the time?
她自己還不是每天都折磨老公
I wasn't talking about you.
我不是說你
Everyone wants you to reconsider this divorce
同學們都希望你不要離婚
and just live with her.
好好跟她在一起
They wanted me to tell you that. Are you crying?
他們要我轉達給你，你在哭嗎？
What? Are you already drunk?
什麼？你已經醉啦？
What is this? You're making my heart flutter.
搞什麼？讓人小鹿亂撞
Am I?
小鹿亂撞嗎？
Apparently, I'm cute when I'm drunk.
人家說我喝醉就會變可愛
-She said that was my special move. -Who said?
-說那是我的殺手鐧 -誰說的？
Hae-in said that.
洪海仁說的
She said
她說
I was cute.
我很可愛
Are you bragging?
你是在炫耀嗎？
Why was I like that?
為什麼我那時候要那樣？
Why was I cute?
為什麼我要變可愛？
Why did I use my special move and look cute?
為什麼我要變可愛，使出殺手鐧？
Why did I make her heart flutter?
讓洪海仁小鹿亂撞？
And as a result,
然後
I ruined
害我毀了
my own life.
自己的人生
We wouldn't have gotten married had I not been so cute.
要是我不可愛，我就不會結這種婚了
This lunatic is totally wasted.
你這個瘋子徹底喝醉了
Hey, get up.
喂，起來
My wife has been calling me, asking me to buy diapers for our baby.
走吧，我老婆從剛才就一直打來說 我小孩的尿布用完了
No, I'm not going home.
不要，我不要走
Why would I?
我為什麼要走？
Why won't you go home?
為什麼不要走？
I'm drunk!
我醉了啊
I'm too cute when I'm drunk!
我喝醉真的很可愛，不能回去
I've always been known as the cute son of the pear tree house in Yongdu-ri.
龍頭里梨樹家的小兒子是天生可愛
It's in my nature.
這是基本配備
I was born like this.
我生出來就是這樣
What could I have done?
我該怎麼辦？
So you're not going home?
所以你不回家？
Just leave me here.
你就把我丟在這裡吧
I'll be taken home safe and sound.
我會被安全送回家
By whom?
怎麼送？
They'll prevent all scandals.
防止緋聞用
No way.
不會吧
Want to see?
你要看看嗎？
Every time…
每次
I tear leaves off a branch
我數樹葉
to see if I should get a divorce or not…
看我要離婚還不離婚的時候
You did that?
你還做那種事喔？
I always end up with a "no."
數出來都是不要離婚
Every single damn time.
數幾次都一樣
So it's your fate.
那就是要你別離
There's no one.
沒有
No one in this world
這個地球上
is on my side.
沒有一個人站在我這邊
There's not a single leaf that's on my side.
連一片樹葉都沒有
I don't need anyone on my side. I just want to own a building.
我不用任何人站在我這邊 只要有棟房子就好了
That building will be on my side forever.
房子永遠都站在我這邊
My wife's mood is like a roller coaster.
老婆每天都在變
She'd be smiling in the morning then raging at night.
早上在哭，晚上又莫名在生氣
Is it my fault we're out of diapers? Why'd she get mad at me?
你看，尿布沒了是我的錯嗎？ 為何要對我發火？
I just need a building.
我只要房子站在我這邊就好了
Concrete buildings don't change.
水泥不會變
They don't nag or get mad.
不會嘮叨，也不會發脾氣
Go.
你走
Go get your diapers.
你去買尿布吧
Just leave.
給我走
Who said
是誰說
Love
愛情
Was beautiful?
很美好？
Just leave already.
你們可以走了
You can go home now.
你們下班吧
You're gonna keep watching me cry?
你們要繼續看我哭嗎？
I'm just crying on my way home!
看我哭要幹嘛？我正在走回家
Why are you going that way?
你們要去哪裡？
Put me to sleep
乾脆用你那雙白皙的手
With your fair hands
哄我入睡
LAWYER IDENTIFICATION CARD BAEK HYUN-WOO
（律師證，白賢祐）
Hey, isn't he the son-in-law of Queens?
喂，他是女王集團的女婿吧？
Son-in-law, my foot. He's pretty much a butler.
哪是什麼女婿？簡直就是管家
I heard he cleans up his in-laws' messes.
聽說他都在幫女王集團裡 闖禍的親戚們擦屁股
Where's his self-respect?
他都沒有自尊心嗎？
He wouldn't have married into that family if he had any.
要是他有就不會為了錢結婚了
He's an embarrassment to all attorneys.
真是律師之恥
Goodness.
唉唷
Oh, my.
天啊
Hallelujah, Hyun-woo.
哈里路亞，白女婿
So what if I have 25 billion won in my account?
戶頭裡有125億韓元有什麼用？
I can't even use it to buy dental floss in here.
在這裡連根牙線都買不了
By the way, how did you come up with this idea?
話說回來，你怎麼會有這個好點子？
Ma'am.
那個…
This is actually illegal, you see.
本來是不可以這樣的
Hyun-woo.
白女婿
How long must I be locked up?
我得在這裡待到什麼時候？
I didn't commit that big of a sin.
我又沒有犯什麼大罪
I thought Seul-hee was the whistleblower who reported me
我只是認為檢舉我貪汙的內部檢舉人
for embezzlement, so I grabbed her hair.
是牟璱凞那女的 所以才稍微抓了她的頭髮
Is that a crime?
這也犯法嗎？
She had to receive treatment for four weeks.
她要四週才能痊癒 應該不是稍微抓而已
Damn it. I should've hospitalized her instead.
可惡，既然要被關 當初就該把她打成18週才能痊癒
She's the reason why my mom passed away.
都是她害我媽過世
Just wait and see. I'll take my revenge on her.
等著瞧，我一定要向她報仇
Hyun-woo.
白女婿
Taking revenge
我的專長是
is my specialty.
報仇
I'm fully aware of that, ma'am.
我非常清楚，姑姑
All three of my ex-husbands have left this country.
跟我離婚的三個人都已經離開韓國了
I brought hell to all of them and their relatives.
因為我把他們全家上下一票親戚 全都給毀了
Ma'am.
那個…姑姑
Married couples can eventually separate.
不想生活在一起，離婚也未嘗不可
So why did you have to go that far?
為何要做到那種程度呢？
Hyun-woo.
白女婿
Divorce is brutal and messy.
離婚是很殘忍不堪的
There's no "good" bye in divorce.
離婚沒有所謂的好好分手
The best solution is for one of them to die.
其中一個死掉還比較乾脆俐落
If I marry and divorce again in the future,
假如我以後再次結婚又離婚
I'll ask you to take my case.
我會委託你當律師
Why are you
為什麼
already thinking about getting another divorce?
你都還沒結婚就想到要離婚？
Whatever.
我不知道啦
For some reason,
很奇怪的是
I think marriage and divorce go hand in hand
我不覺得結婚和幸福是一組的
instead of marriage and happiness.
結婚和離婚才是
I agree.
我也這麼認為
What did you say?
你說什麼？
Nothing.
沒有
Hey. Look here.
喂，你看我這裡
I lost a lot of hair, right?
我頭頂掉了很多頭髮吧？
I really need to get out of here.
我得離開這裡
This place is teeming with bitches.
這裡全都是壞女人
I'm going to become like them if I stay here any longer.
我再待下去我也會跟著歪掉
My mom's memorial service is coming up.
過不久就是我媽的忌日
My dad will settle this before then
我爸要是有良心
for her sake, right?
就會在那之前和解吧？
I'm currently in front of Queens Town
記者現在所在的位置是
in Hanil-dong, Yongsan-gu, Seoul where the memorial service
首爾龍山區漢日洞女王城前
of Yang Mi-suk, the Queens' chairman's late wife,
女王集團洪滿臺會長的已故妻子
is taking place.
楊美淑女士的祭祀在此舉行
The family members are arriving one by one.
女王集團家族的人一一抵達
This year, Hong Beom-seok, the chairman's eldest son
今年洪滿臺會長的長子
and former CEO of Queens Distribution,
前女王流通的代表洪凡錫
flew in from Hawaii.
從美國夏威夷臨時歸國
There is a keen interest
長久以來不和的
in whether or not the chairman and his son will reconcile
洪滿臺與洪凡錫父子是否會見面
after their long-time feud.
備受關注
Sir, can you take a look at my pancakes? Do you think the insides are cooked?
大哥，可以幫我看一下煎餅嗎？ 這樣裡面熟了嗎？
Why would you ask me that?
為什麼要問我？
You studied chemistry in Harvard,
你在哈佛不是主修化學嗎？
so I thought you'd know.
我想你應該很了解
Yes. Judging by the color,
嗯，變成這種黃色
I'm sure they're well-cooked. Flip them.
裡面應該充分熟了，翻面
Yes, sir. I'll do the plating.
好，我來擺盤
Was it you who graduated from Parsons School of Design?
金女婿是帕森設計學院畢業的吧？
No, that's me.
喔，那是我
His family have been architects for generations.
他們家代代都是建築師
His family made the big sculpture
羅浮宮前面的大型雕塑
-in front of the Louvre. -I'll be honest.
-就是他們家做的 -坦白講
I'm pretty confident about stacking up food.
我對堆疊食物有信心
What a waste of talent.
根本是浪費才能
My dear brothers-in-law.
姐夫們
This is Mr. Choi. He married Min-hee, our relative.
這位是上個月 和小叔家的敏熙結婚的崔女婿
My brothers-in-law.
這些都是姐夫
Hello.
大家好
In the past, powerful families such as royalty
聽說古代王室或是門第高的家族
made the male members prepare everything for memorial services.
祭祀從頭到尾都是由男人在準備
The chairman has great interest in royal traditions,
我們會長喜歡王室的傳統
I see.
這樣啊
This must be why traditions and the future go well together.
所以說傳統與未來是相通的
This isn't old-fashioned. It's quite progressive and nice.
這樣不會墨守成規，相當進步又美好
It fits the current trend.
又符合趨勢潮流
If it's so progressive, nice, and trendy,
這麼進步、美好，又符合趨勢潮流
why don't you join us?
那你怎麼不一起呢？
You know me.
你也知道啊
I've been going to church since last year,
我從去年開始上教會
so this is against my religion.
不太適合準備祭祀
I was born a Christian.
我一出生就信教了
Ever since I was young,
我從小時候
I've had a condition
就有種不能聞到油味的
where I can't smell oil. It's a shame.
一種慢性病，真不好意思
Thank you for your hard work.
那麼各位辛苦了
Good luck.
加油
-Gosh. -Seriously?
-唉 -真是的
This is the Hong family's memorial service.
坦白講，這是洪氏祖先的祭祀
But no one here has that surname.
準備的人卻是姓金、姓劉 姓趙和姓白的
They should prepare their own memorial services.
姓洪的祭祀就該由姓洪的自己準備
-Jeez. -I'm the fifth only son
-唉 -我是白川劉氏
of the Yu family in Paechon County, 39th generation.
第39代，五代單傳
What would my mother say if she saw me complete this skewer in ten seconds?
我媽看到我十秒就能串一串肉串 不知道會怎麼說？
Let's not talk about how precious we are
我們就別提我們在各自家裡
to our families.
是多麼寶貝的兒子吧
Welcome to Queens.
歡迎你來到女王家族
-Welcome.
-歡迎
But if I were you,
不過如果我是你
I'd run away right now.
我現在就會逃跑
It's not too late since it's his first memorial service.
才第一次祭祀，還不遲
How's the color? Does it look too dull?
這個顏色可以嗎？不會太暗嗎？
Jade green isn't an easy color.
翡翠色很難穿起來好看
I've only seen two people who looked good in that color.
我這輩子就只見過 兩個很適合翡翠色的人
You
那就是夫人你
and Yuna Kim at the London Fashion Show.
還有在倫敦時尚秀上的金妍兒
Oh, her? Yes, she looked really nice.
喔，金妍兒？她真的很適合
And so do you, ma'am.
你可不亞於她
You know how to please others.
你還真會說話
Ms. Moh.
牟女士
Why aren't you wearing the hanbok that was sent to you?
幫你準備了韓服，你怎麼不穿呢？
I shouldn't be at this memorial service.
我怎麼能參與這個祭祀？
The family can do it without me.
你們一家人好好祭拜就好了
You've been with us for over 20 years, so you're family too.
同住在一個屋簷下超過20年 就算是家人了
That's what a family is.
家人不就是這樣嗎？
That's very kind of you. But I'll just stay in my room.
很感謝你這麼說
People will talk
別人會罵說
about how I shove you around and mistreat you.
我只會使喚你，沒有好好對待你
"Shove you around"? Who shoves whom?
使喚？誰使喚誰？
Do you shove her around?
你使喚她嗎？
Me? Shove her?
我使喚牟女士嗎？
No, Father. Never.
不是的，爸，這怎麼可能？
Then why would you say that?
那你為什麼要那麼說？
You only said that because that's how you think of her.
你平常都是那麼想，才會那麼說
That's not why.
不是這樣的
She didn't want to wear a hanbok.
她執意不肯穿韓服
-Why not? -I don't know.
-為什麼不穿？ -就是說啊
Are you not going to?
你不穿嗎？
Of course, I will.
我當然要穿，會長
You heard her.
她說要穿啊
Let's go.
走吧
What a crazy…
怎麼會有這種瘋女人？
Gosh, I'm so stressed.
唉唷，氣死
She's a sly one.
真是高段
She's going to brazenly attend Ms. Yang's memorial service
她不看任何人的臉色
because the chairman insisted.
因為會長堅持要這麼做
That's her plan.
她就是想要這樣
Who knew a girlfriend-in-law could be worse than a mother-in-law?
比婆婆還更可怕的是公公的女友
Beom-ja is here!
凡資來了！
Hyun-woo.
白女婿
Why did she get discharged today?
她怎麼會今天出獄？
You said she'd get sick if she stayed locked up in this cold.
您說天氣冷在看守所裡會生病 要我把她弄出來
Right.
喔，對
I did say that.
我這麼說過
Still, you should've waited to let her out after the memorial service.
不過應該等祭祀完再讓她出來
What? Look at that good-for-nothing.
嗯？你看看那個無賴
Just look at her.
你看看她
I was thoughtless, sir.
是我思考不周
Mom.
媽
I was locked up.
你女兒從看守所回來了
Dad put his one and only daughter behind bars
我只不過是稍微抓了他情人的頭髮 稍微踢了她幾下
just because I grabbed his girlfriend by the hair and kicked her.
一個做父親的人
Hey.
喂
It's the truth.
我有說錯嗎？
You're head over heels for her.
你再怎麼被女人給迷得神魂顛倒
Not only are you in love with the woman who killed your wife,
也不該袒護把自己老婆給氣死的女人
but you sent your daughter to jail.
還把女兒給送進大牢吧
You're absolutely heartless.
你真的好無情
Beom-ja, this is Mom's memorial service. Let's talk later. Okay?
凡資，這是媽媽的祭祀 下次再說，好嗎？
You're no different. Have you forgotten who she is?
你也是一樣
Mom died because of her!
我們的媽媽是被誰害死的？
Mom died of a heart attack--
媽只是心臟麻痺…
Exactly! Why do you think she had it?
對啊！媽怎麼會心臟麻痺呢？
Her heart stopped because she was enraged at Moh Seul-hee!
還不是因為牟璱凞那女的 才會氣到心臟麻痺！
So how can you stand looking at her every day and night?
可是你卻
Are you not upset?
你沒有自尊嗎？
-Beom-ja, I-- -Gosh, Mom.
凡資，我…
What's the point of having a son?
養兒子有什麼用？
You didn't even prepare skate, her favorite food,
連媽最喜歡的斑鰩都沒有準備
so who are you to talk?
是要拜什麼？
Aunt Beom-ja, we have skate. The house reeks of it.
姑姑，斑鰩在那裡啊 味道都傳到這裡來了
Get lost, you bastard!
你滾開，臭小子！
How could you never visit me when I raised you myself?
身為姪子都沒來探過監
You didn't raise him.
我們家秀哲怎麼會是你養的？
Don't be ridiculous.
真是胡說八道
Aunt Beom-ja.
姑姑
We were just serving the alcohol.
我們剛才正在奉酒
Really?
是喔？
We should continue then. Go on.
要奉酒沒錯，奉吧
What's wrong with you?
你為什麼要這樣？
Come on.
真是的
Hey, turn the glass slowly.
喂，慢慢轉杯子
She was a lightweight. You're going to get her drunk!
我媽酒量不好，喝太快會醉！
Beom-ja.
凡資
Mom drank like a fish.
媽是酒鬼
That's a fact we both know to be true.
這是你我皆知，千真萬確的事實
Why do you think she drank so much?
媽為什麼會變成酒鬼？
Because that woman stressed her out!
還不是因為她造成媽壓力大！
Uncle.
舅舅
Doesn't it break your heart to know that your sister passed away
想到媽被牟璱凞那女的氣死而過世
because she was outraged by that woman? Say something!
肯定讓你痛徹心扉吧？你說句話啊
Beom-ja, that's not why she died.
凡資，姐不是氣死的 她是心臟麻痺沒錯
Goodness.
唉
Mom.
媽
This family is a total disaster.
這個家真是烏煙瘴氣，亂七八糟
Don't bother visiting.
你不需要過來
I'll drink the alcohol.
酒由我來喝
You should make a U-turn.
你就調頭回去吧
Mr. Hong, you finally came back after 19 years. Will you rejoin Queens--
洪凡錫代表，你時隔19年才回來 可以將此視為你回歸女王…
Will you be attending your mother's memorial service?
你今天會參加你母親的祭祀嗎？
Will you be meeting Chairman Hong?
你與洪滿臺會長約好要見面嗎？
Have you two reconciled?
你們要和好嗎？
Please sit. He'll leave eventually.
坐下吧，他等一下就會走了
That's why I despise him more.
這樣更令人討厭
That bastard didn't come to see me.
那個不肖子不是來看我
He came to get his photo taken.
而是來給記者拍照的
Look at him.
你看看他
He's purposely standing in the rain for the cameras.
故意在鏡頭前面淋雨
What a bastard.
那個不肖子
We're the ones who cooked all those pancakes.
煎餅煎到累歪的是我們
Do you see my hands trembling?
你看我的手在抖
But they don't even allow us to attend the service.
在祭拜的卻只有他們自己人
These days, I spend a lot of time on internet forums about mothers.
最近我愛看的社群都是媽媽論壇
I can relate to many of their posts.
那裡有超多讓我有共鳴的文章
I don't remember the last time I visited my parents on the holidays.
過年過節都只有在岳家 我都不記得我哪時回我家了
They said they'd let us go once we cleaned up.
他們說只要收完供桌就會讓我們走
-"Wait for your aunt-in-law." -Right.
-“見完阿姨再走” -對
"Wait for your uncle-in-law."
“見完小堂叔再走”
"Chop some apples."
-又要我們削蘋果 -對
"Serve the pancakes."
去分煎餅給大家
I mean, what about our families?
只有岳家的人是家人嗎？
Today is Hyun-woo's father's birthday.
賢祐大哥的爸爸今天生日
It's his 60th birthday.
而且是60大壽
But he couldn't visit him because of this memorial service.
因為忌日和生日撞期 他一次都沒能回去
Anyway, I pity him the most.
總之他最可憐了
-Me too.
-是啊
Our wives are their cousins, but he married the direct line. Gosh.
我們是表親
His in-laws
他們那家人
are all terrifying.
都很可怕啊
-They are.
-對啊
Director Jo.
我們的趙理事
You've been attending the memorial service for 20 years now.
來祭拜我媽已經有20年了
She always treated me well. Of course I should come.
會長夫人在世的時候
I know you submitted your resignation letter,
我看了你的辭呈
but I really don't want to accept it.
但是我真的不想受理
I thought long and hard before making that decision.
這是我思考許久下的決定
Soon, I'll be too old to have a fresh start.
如果現在不辭，應該很難再重新出發
Okay. It can't be helped then.
好吧，那我也沒辦法
I'll always be rooting for you.
我會永遠支持你
Thank you so much, sir.
副會長，真的非常感謝你
Look into him. It's odd for him to quit so suddenly.
去查個清楚，他突然這樣很可疑
I'm sure something's up.
肯定有什麼問題
I'll look into him discreetly.
我會悄悄去查
No, everyone should know about this.
不對，這種事就要鬧得沸沸揚揚
Find out what he did and let the media see him going to court.
先找出他的嫌疑
My purpose isn't to punish him.
目的不是要讓他受罰
It's to humiliate him.
而是要讓他身敗名裂
Why do you wish to do that?
這麼做有什麼理由嗎？
I never allow those who turn their backs on me
當在我們家吃過飯的人要背離我
to leave in one piece.
不能讓他們安然離去
They need to suffer on their way out
至少要讓他們無法好端端地走出去
so they won't cause further troubles.
才不會有後患
What's with the face?
你怎麼會那副表情？
Do you have something to say?
你有什麼話要說嗎？
But he devoted many years to you.
可是他付出了這麼長的歲月
Is it right to cut him off
這樣斷了他的手腳
so brutally?
究竟對嗎？
That's probably what he'll think.
他應該會這麼想
But that's his opinion.
可是這只是他個人的想法
I believe an organization must follow its rules.
我認為組織要有組織的原則
That's exactly right.
我就是這個意思
It's not just him. I'm after anyone else who has the same idea.
整一個人的時候，不是只有在整他 同時也在警告偷偷有二心的人
It's a warning to those who want to backstab me.
以及準備要在背後捅我一刀的人
-Yes, sir. -Keep that in mind.
-是 -你也要銘記在心
-Sorry? -You should never bid farewell
-什麼？ -不能對背離我的人
to those who abandon you.
揮揮手說再見
You must stab them in the back.
而是要捅他們一刀
Yes, sir.
是
Well done.
辛苦你了
Go rest up.
回去好好休息吧
Yes, sir.
是
Goodbye then.
那我回去了
I don't have an appetite.
我沒有胃口
It feels like my appetite is completely gone.
而且是食慾全然消失的感覺
It's suffocating to be around many people.
到人多的地方就會覺得喘不過氣
Your stress levels seem to be extremely high.
你的壓力似乎相當大
Based on your sentence completion test,
我看你填寫的完成句子測驗
you wrote that your biggest desire right now
你寫說現在最想做的事
is getting a divorce.
是離婚
-Correct. -I see. And why is that?
-對 -嗯，有什麼理由嗎？
I live with my parents-in-law.
我跟岳父岳母住在一起
And my grandfather-in-law.
還有岳祖父
And him.
還有岳祖父啊
As well as my recently-discharged aunt-in-law
再加上不久前出獄的岳姑姑
and my brother-in-law's family.
以及小舅子一家人
We all live
我們全都
under the same roof.
同住在一個屋簷下
I see.
這樣啊
It's rare to see extended families nowadays. You're blessed.
這是很罕見的大家庭
We're so blessed that we have dinner together every night.
我們太有福了，每天晚餐都一起吃
Then we get together at 9:00 p.m. to talk.
到了晚上九點 還有大家聚在一起聊天的時間
An end-of-day meeting.
就像是每日總結會議
The weekends, holidays, birthdays, and Christmas.
週末、假日、生日、聖誕節
We spend them together all year round. It's safe to say
全都要一起過，可以說是一年365天
that I have no time for myself.
都沒有我自己的時間
We have 15 memorial services per year.
一年有15次祭祀
They say noble families in the past
他們說古代真正的貴族家裡
made their male members prepare for the services.
都是由男人在準備祭祀
So the sons-in-law prepare for the entire service.
因此要女婿們從頭準備到尾
But their sons never help.
卻不讓他們兒子的手沾到一滴水
It feels like
看來
you need a place where you can be away from them.
你需要有個可以喘口氣的地方
Do you have a job?
請問你有工作嗎？
-Yes. -Good.
-有 -很好
How's your work life?
職場生活如何？
My wife is my boss.
我老婆是我上司
And my father-in-law is her boss.
我老婆的上司是我岳父
Then my grandfather-in-law
岳父的上司
My heart races, and my hands tremble
只要我手機畫面跳出我岳家人的名字
whenever my in-laws call.
我就會心跳加速，雙手發抖
I'm anxious about what they'll ask me to do.
不知道這次又要使喚我什麼事
Why don't you distance yourself from this stressful environment?
你要不要脫離讓你有壓力的環境呢？
Then divorce is the only option.
那就只有離婚這個選擇了
You could move out with your wife.
不是還可以分家嗎？
It's true that I dislike my in-laws. However…
我的確是討厭我岳家人，可是…
I despise my wife even more.
我更討厭我老婆
Why is that?
為什麼？
She doesn't care
她不管
at all about me or how her family treats me.
我被她家人怎麼對待、有沒有吃飯
She only cares about herself. Isn't she selfish?
她只知道她自己，真的很自私吧？
I only married into the family because of her
我就為了她一個人進到這個家來
and endured three years of this treatment.
被折磨了三年
But she doesn't care.
她卻坐視不管
Before we got married, she said I could trust her.
要結婚的時候
I'm the only one you need.
你看著我就好
Just trust me.
相信我
I will never
我絕對
make you cry.
不會讓你流淚
I was an idiot for believing her.
是我太傻才相信她
Are you hurt and upset with her?
你對你老婆有些失望嗎？
No.
沒有
I no longer feel that way.
我不再覺得失望
I just despise her.
我討厭她
I hate her
我真的討厭她
with a passion.
討厭得不得了
And that's why you want a divorce.
所以你才想要離婚
That's the only way I'll live.
這樣我才能活下去
Then why haven't you?
那你為什麼還不離婚？
Because I could die.
因為我可能會死
What?
什麼？
My father-in-law
我岳父
despises it the most when his people
最討厭在他家吃過飯的人
turn their backs on him.
背離他
The moment I divorce her,
一旦我背他而去
he'll stab me in the back.
他會在我背上捅一刀
Stab you?
捅一刀？
Of course, that was a figure of speech.
當然不是真的捅一刀
But getting stabbed might actually be better.
但真的捅或許還比較好
I'll prescribe you something strong, so take it.
我幫你開了很強的藥，請你好好吃
Hang in there.
加油
Goodbye.
再見
WIFE
（老婆）
I love you, honey.
老婆，我愛你
I genuinely think I'm happy.
我想我真的很幸福
I didn't do anything.
我哪有闖禍？
I'm just really grateful--
我只是對一切覺得感謝…
Hello?
喂？
I'm so happy.
我真幸福
Wait, Grace.
我說葛瑞絲
Why aren't you saying anything?
你講話怎麼能講到一半？
You should take responsibility for saying
你說進成集團的三兒子 是真正的好對象
that Jinseong Group's third heir was the real deal.
那你就要負責啊
Why should I do that?
我為什麼要負那個責任？
I heard you chose their eldest son. Go on that blind date then.
你不是安排和他們家長子相親了嗎？ 那就去啊
But the chairman doesn't like him.
但進成集團會長不喜歡他
So how can I set my daughter up with him
我怎麼能讓我女兒跟他相親？
when I heard that his third son will inherit everything?
我聽說他會把財產都留給三兒子
You should've come to me first.
那你當初就應該要先來找我
You already set up a blind date with the eldest son, a rogue.
你都約好跟無賴長子相親了
So what can I do?
我能怎麼辦？
You should just go to that matchmaker.
你去找幫你牽線的人
I was in a dilemma.
我也是很苦惱
What choice did I have when I heard that you were no longer competent?
老實說我聽說
What did you say?
你說什麼？
So what if you serve the ladies of Queens?
你整天黏著女王集團家的夫人們 有什麼用？
You may oversee their household matters, but your daughter is still single.
你照顧他們家的大小事
That's exactly why
所以
Hong Hae-in regrets not listening to me and marrying her now-husband.
不聽我的話，隨心所欲結婚的洪海仁
Seriously?
真的嗎？
Are they getting a divorce?
那他們要離婚嗎？
You can't be with someone who's out of your league.
階級是種科學
Three years is enough.
三年已經夠久了
Just wait and see.
等著瞧吧
Even the great Hong Hae-in
天下無敵的洪海仁
will listen to me when she wants to remarry.
要再婚的時候也會對我服服貼貼
Ms. Hong!
洪社長！
Your mother stopped by our spa this morning.
今天早上你媽媽有到我們店裡來
I told you to come by. Why won't you?
我就要你也過來，你怎麼都不來呢？
Are you stressed out these days?
最近你壓力很大嗎？
Your skin looks dull.
你的皮膚大不如前耶
We have some great serums and machines.
我們店裡進了超讚的安瓶和機器
I'll empty out our schedule, so do stop by.
我會抽出時間來，你一定過來一趟
You must be busy, so you don't need to do that.
你應該很忙，不需要這樣
We're not busy.
我不忙
You worry so much about me!
洪社長還真是為我著想！
No, I don't.
我不是在為你著想
What?
嗯？
I'm just saying that I will never visit your spa.
我的意思是說我不會去你的美容院
You're so cold.
你個性還真冷淡
You're making me feel distant.
真是讓人有距離感
You should feel that way.
必須要讓你有距離感
You must be treating me
你好像感覺不到距離感
like a friend because you think we're close.
所以才都不跟我說敬語，還碰我
I hope you'll be more careful. It's uncomfortable.
希望你注意一點
But--
那個…
She has a nasty temper.
她的脾氣還真不是蓋的
She's so obnoxious. Don't you agree?
實在是有夠沒禮貌，對吧？
The third heir of Jinseong Group
進成集團的三兒子
is into vegan food these days.
最近迷的是純素食品
A vegan forum will be held at their hotel next Friday.
下週五在進成飯店有個純素論壇
Bring your daughter there.
帶你女兒去那裡吧
-I'll try to set them up. -Really?
-我幫你牽線 -真的嗎？
You can go now.
那你走吧
I have something to do.
我還有事要辦
I knew it.
不愧是葛瑞絲
I trust you, Grace.
我都聽你的
You see,
話說
I've been in the beauty industry
我這輩子都只有從事美容業
and matchmaking wealthy families
還有幫好人家的子女們作媒
all my life.
做這些事情而已
So I don't know much about legal matters.
所以不太懂法律和文書等等
I see. What is this about?
是，請問有什麼事嗎？
I'm sure you heard
你應該有聽說吧？
that Daegyeong's youngest son passed away due to a car accident.
大慶集團的小兒子車禍過世了
I did.
有
It seems like
可是他的妻子
his wife won't inherit any of his fortunes.
一毛都繼承不了他的財產
Turns out, her husband had written a will
原來是他在結婚前
before they got married.
就先立好遺囑了
He said his children, nieces, or nephews
他說死後要把全部的財產
should inherit his fortunes instead if he died.
交給他的子女或姪子，而不給配偶
But that couple never had a child.
可是他們還沒有孩子
In that case, the wife could claim
這種情況，可以主張特留分
a legal reserve of inheritance and file a lawsuit.
並且提出要求返還的訴訟
I can introduce you to an attorney if you want.
有需要的話 我可以幫你介紹專門的律師
What for? I have you.
為什麼？你就是專家啦
You're in the same boat.
你也是當事人
Sorry?
什麼？
Ms. Hong also wrote a will before she got married.
洪海仁社長在婚前也有立遺囑啊
Didn't you know?
你不知道嗎？
You must've thought
你以為簽了婚前協議書
the prenuptial agreement was it.
就沒問題啦
I can't believe she didn't tell you.
她居然沒跟你說這件事？
She's a heartless one.
洪社長果然是個可怕的人
The will said that Queens
她說如果她有什麼不測
would inherit all her cash, stocks, and real estates
她名下的現金、股票和不動產
if something happened to her.
全部都要留給女王集團
She said you wouldn't get anything.
不給你一毛錢
She wrote it in such detail.
寫得非常嚴謹
We use that as a template for all future wills.
那在我們這個圈子裡
What's with that face?
你怎麼會那副表情？
Did you really think it was the marriage of the century
你該不會以為你們的婚姻
that transcended all backgrounds
真的就像報導上寫的一樣
like the media claimed it was?
是超越階級的世紀之愛吧？
Don't be so naive.
你也太天真了吧
Ms. Hong didn't want a husband.
洪社長打從一開始就不是要丈夫
She wanted a slave she could add to the family register.
而是在找可以登記到戶籍上的長工
And that's when you appeared.
而你正好映入她的眼簾
You're handsome and intelligent. It was the best PR she could have.
你長得帥，又是首爾大學畢業 正適合做為宣傳愛情故事用
You're obedient just to her liking.
你又很聽話，很好使喚
The only problem was the wealth dispute,
只有一個問題是以後的財產糾紛
but that's solved, thanks to the will.
但是已經白紙黑字寫下來了
That's enough.
請別說了
Okay.
好
Hello, Professor.
喂？教授
Can you e-mail it to me? I don't have time to go there.
請寄電子郵件給我，我沒有時間過去
Why weren't you picking up?
你為什麼不接電話？
We need to go somewhere.
跟我去個地方
I know you're free today. I checked.
你之後沒有行程，我都確認過了
The car is waiting downstairs.
車子在樓下等了
I'm not going.
我不去
I didn't even tell you where we were going.
我又沒說要去哪裡
It doesn't matter.
去哪裡都無所謂
I refuse to go anywhere with you.
因為我哪裡都不跟你去
So…
話說
here's what Yongdu-ri thinks.
目前龍頭里的民意是
They don't mind you serving consecutive terms.
白斗關里長連任沒有問題
That's the general opinion.
大概是這種氣氛
Stop by my shop later for a snack. The new makgeolli tastes good.
待會點心時間到我店裡去
Again?
又有啦？
-You're always so generous. -Gosh.
-你每次都這麼慷慨 -唉唷
I wish I could give you something better, but there's
我心裡是想給你更好的東西
the Improper Solicitation and Graft Act.
但是有《金英蘭法》
The village head is also a state job,
里長也是公職人員
so I can't be too generous.
私下能給的有限
Gosh, I'm always grateful.
唉唷，我一直都很感激
You've done enough already.
這樣就夠了
-You understand, right? -Of course.
-你能理解吧？ -嗯
Goodness, Ms. Jeon.
唉唷，大嫂
Hello.
你出來啦？
-Jeez. -Hey.
-唉唷 -你來啦？
Did it get stuck again?
又陷進去啦？
You idiots. How can you call yourselves farmers?
你們這兩個傢伙真的是農夫嗎？
How do you manage to get the cultivator
怎麼會每次把耕耘機開出來
stuck every time?
就會卡住呢？
What took you so long?
你怎麼那麼慢才來？
I--
我只是…
I'm not 911. I can't always come right away.
我又不是消防隊，一叫就會過來
My wife used to drive a cultivator
我老婆在跟我結婚前
and catch small octopuses in Beolgyo, Jeolla Province
可是在全羅道筏橋泥灘
before marrying me.
開著耕耘機抓長蛸的女人
She's really something.
非常厲害
It's working!
好了
Gosh, what lovely weather.
唉呀，天氣真好
What? Hey.
嗯？
Yeong-cheol! How are your mother's knees?
嘿，永哲，你媽媽的膝蓋還好嗎？
They're the same!
老樣子！
That's why she needs to take glucosamine!
所以說她要吃葡萄糖胺啦！
-Sit down! -Okay.
-坐下啦 -好
Isn't your son taking his midterms soon?
你兒子過兩天是不是要期中考？
What's it to me? It's his work.
又不是我要考，是他要考
What are you saying?
你在說什麼？
Even still, you should help him memorize!
不管如何
When Hyun-woo went to SNU, I helped him day and night--
我們家賢祐在考首爾大學的時候 我早晚都盯他的背誦科目…
Why did you suddenly speed up?
你幹嘛突然加速？
I told you to sit, didn't I?
我分明有叫你坐下了
They may just look like normal farmers, but they're more than that.
雖然這裡看起來都是蒜頭田和玉米田
They're all voters.
這些都是票倉
The reelection is around the corner. You know nothing.
就要選連任了，你都不懂
Reelection, my foot.
管他什麼選舉
We need to take care of our grove and our shop.
光是忙果園和商店
We're already juggling so much.
就已經忙得要死了
Didn't I tell you countless times
你就趁這個機會別做里長了
to give up your position?
我都說過幾次了？
Honey.
老婆
I'm only doing this for balance's sake.
我是為了平衡才這麼做
-What balance? -Hear me out.
-平衡什麼？ -你看喔
Hyun-woo's in-laws may be the pillars of this country's economy,
賢祐岳家在經濟上是韓國的支柱
but they don't have much political power.
但是在政界沒有什麼影響力
Our families can only have balance
而我在地方上
since I'm maintaining
佔據了政界要職
my important post as the village head.
就可以大致維持平衡了
Why are you stopping now?
你為什麼又要急煞？
-Hyun-woo! -What?
-賢祐 -嗯？
You didn't even call.
你怎麼都沒先說一聲？
I just thought I'd visit.
我突然想回來
Where's Hae-in?
我們家媳婦呢？
Are you here alone again?
你又自己一個人來啦？
Have you eaten yet?
吃過飯了嗎？
Not yet.
還沒
Okay.
好
This looks ripe.
熟透了
Move aside.
讓開
Let's see.
讓我看看
Move. My youngest son is here.
讓開，我們家小兒子回來了
Gosh, you must've been hungry.
唉唷，你很餓啊
Take your time.
慢慢吃
Is it good?
好吃嗎？
Yes, I'm busy. Why?
嗯，我很忙，怎樣？
Hyun-woo is here?
賢祐來了？
One minute.
請等一下
QUEEN'S HAIR SALON
（女王美髮沙龍）
That little scumbag.
白賢祐那個臭小子
He didn't even come for Dad's 60th birthday.
要他來幫爸過60大壽都不見蹤影
Don't let him leave.
把他留住，別讓他走
I've been meaning to ask you something.
我一直想要說你幾句
I'm disappointed in both you and Hae-in.
你和弟媳怎麼可以這樣？
I get that you can't come regularly or even on the holidays.
平時不來也好，過節不來就算了
But shouldn't you have attended Dad's 60th birthday?
可是爸的60大壽應該要回來才對吧？
-That's so heartless. -Yes, you're right.
-這樣太過分了 -對，沒錯
I was heartless.
太過分了
At least he knows that he was wrong.
你知道很過分嘛
That's why I'm getting a divorce.
所以我打算離婚
-What? -Dad. Mom.
-什麼？ -爸，媽
I'm going to divorce Hae-in.
我打算和海仁離婚
-I'm sorry. -Wait.
-對不起 -等等
Hey, don't tell me
你該不會是因為
you're getting a divorce just because of what I said.
60大壽沒回來就要離婚吧？
What's with you? 60th birthdays are nothing.
你是怎麼了？60大壽又沒什麼
Birthdays come every year.
生日每年都會有
Indeed. Who celebrates 60th birthdays these days?
對啊，最近誰還在過60大壽？
Forget 70th too. We're expected to live longer lives.
70歲都沒在慶祝了 現在是百歲時代
It's not because of that.
不是因為這個關係
Then?
不然呢？
What is it? I'm sure you have a reason.
是怎麼回事？應該有什麼原因吧
Don't tell me you're seeing another--
難道你有別的女人…
Come on.
拜託
No.
不是
Then does Hae-in have--
那是媳婦有別的男人…
Can you please stop?
你也真是的
That's not true either. It's just too much for me.
不是這樣
I'm not happy.
生活也不幸福
That's an absurd reason.
這什麼不像話的理由
Do you think I'm always happy?
你以為我每天都很幸福嗎？
He's right.
就是說啊
Your dad isn't always happy in this marriage either.
你爸也不是天天都幸福
If anything, I'm miserable.
反而是很不幸
But I'm only able to endure it
只是非常偶爾意外地
because of the smallest happiness
難得有一天覺得幸福
that I feel once in a blue moon.
我就是靠著那一天撐下來
-That's marriage. That's life. -You know what you're talking about.
這就是婚姻，就是人生
I'll be honest.
坦白講
Do you think I'm with your mom because I love her?
你以為我是愛你媽 才跟她生活在一起嗎？
What did you say?
你說什麼？
I'm not done.
聽我說完
Of course, I love you.
我當然愛你
But if love is the only thing you feel,
可是成天只有愛而已
then that'll be the death of you.
那會死人的
Sure. I hope you live a long life.
對，你就長命百歲吧
Look at this.
你看看
We still fail to see eye to eye despite being married for 40 years.
我們一起生活了40多年 還是這麼無法心靈相通
Not at all.
完全無法
Unbelievable.
唉，真是的
I understand.
我明白你們的意思
But…
可是
I thought long and hard before making this decision.
這真的是我深思熟慮後才做的決定
I'm going to do it.
我會離婚
I'm sorry.
對不起
Stop!
停！停車！
Stop! Get out, you scumbag!
停！你這個混帳東西，下車！
You're so selfish.
你真的都只有考慮自己
Don't you know I had to make sacrifices for you?
你以為沒有我的犧牲 你能坐上那個位置嗎？
What sacrifices?
你犧牲了什麼？
I couldn't even go to university because our parents sold
爸媽為了送你上首爾大學把牛都賣了
all of our cows to send you to Seoul.
害我上不了大學
How could you forget that?
你都沒有想過嗎？
How are you so shameless? You couldn't go to university
你有良心嗎？你上不了大學
because you failed at attendance.
只是因為你出席率不足
This boy is so naive.
你只知其一，不知其二
Why do you think Grand Prince Yang-nyeong acted out?
你以為讓寧大君為什麼會這麼脫序？
What are you on about?
你又在說什麼了？
It was a sacrifice.
他是在犧牲
He sacrificed himself and acted out for his brother Se-jong's sake.
他是為了世宗才故意過得放蕩不羈
Do you think I enjoyed acting out?
你以為我覺得脫序好玩嗎？
I gave up our parents' expectations, hopes, and cows
我是因為想要把父母期待和希望 還有賣牛的錢
just for you.
都讓你獨享才這樣
You did?
你是這樣嗎？
Yes, me.
對啊，我就是這樣
I had to make sacrifices as the eldest.
我就是犧牲奉獻的長女
Hey!
喂！
That was ages ago.
你在說那什麼幾百年前的事
I'm leaving.
我要走了
I don't want to pressure you.
我不想要給你壓力
You already are.
已經給了
-I'm only worried about Dad. -What about him?
-我真的是很擔心爸 -爸怎樣？
Do you know how happy he was to marry you off to Queens?
你知道你當了女王家的女婿後
He says he has no appetite but finishes a bowl of rice soup
他本來沒胃口 看到女王集團的股價上漲
every time Queens' stock prices go up.
就馬上把飯泡浸湯裡吃完一整碗
He always enjoyed rice soup.
爸本來就喜歡泡飯吃
Yes, that's true.
嗯，這倒是沒錯
Right. But…
沒錯，可是
A son from this tiny town gets a divorce?
在這個小村子裡，有兒子離婚
He'll be humiliated! Wake up, you idiot!
他會丟臉丟盡，你清醒點，臭小子
This isn't Seoul or Hollywood.
這裡不是首爾也不是好萊塢
This is Yongdu-ri.
這裡是龍頭里
Your friend Chang-sik got divorced two years ago,
你朋友昌植前年離婚
and they're still talking about it.
到現在都還是大家八卦的話題
He's right.
對啊，他說的沒錯
All the ladies at my hair salon
每次婆婆媽媽們到我的髮廊來
still wonder why he got divorced.
都是在聊昌植為何會被離婚
That's right. However…
對啊，可是
no one will talk about him if you get divorced too.
要是你離婚 就不會再有人聊昌植的事了
Is this because of your gym's rent?
你是為了拳擊館的租金才這樣嗎？
And because of Gyeong-jun who's studying abroad?
而你是為了景俊的留學經費？
Since you need to send him money?
因為你要供他讀書？
Are you using me to live comfortable lives
你們要像賣沈清換三百石供米一樣
just like how Sim-cheong was sold for 300 sacks of rice?
賣掉我的人生過上好日子嗎？
Gosh. No, I…
唉唷，我…
I wouldn't use you if it was that much.
如果是這種規模，我不會把你賣了
-But it's not. -Damn it.
-可是又不是這樣 -唉唷
Hey, Hyun-woo.
喂，賢祐
Hyun--
賢…
Hyun-woo!
賢祐
-Baek Hyun-woo! -Hyun-woo!
-白賢祐！ -賢祐！
Stay the night!
住一晚再走！
DIVORCE SETTLEMENT AGREEMENT
（離婚協議書）
I have
我…
something to say.
有話要跟你說
I'll go first.
我先說
What?
什麼？
I do too, so let me go first.
我也有話要說，所以我先說
Okay. Go on.
好，你先說
I'm…
我…
dying.
就要死了
I have three months left.
剩下三個月左右
What did you say?
你說什麼？
I said we had to go somewhere today.
我剛才不是說要去個地方嗎？
I went to the hospital.
我去了醫院
And the doctor said I was dying
醫生說我就快死了
and that I had three months.
說我剩下三個月左右的生命
What…
那是
are you saying?
什麼意思？
It's exactly what I said.
就是我字面上說的意思
The doctor said I only have three months to live.
醫生說我只剩下三個月可以活了
That's all.
我要說的說完了
-What did you want to say? -What?
-你要說什麼？ -嗯？
You had something to say. What is it?
你不是說有話要說嗎？你要說什麼？
I don't think
我想
that's important right now.
那些現在不重要了
Just say it. I know you have something to say.
你說啊，你不是有話要說嗎？
Well, I…
那個，所以說…
-So what… -Yes?
-就是說… -嗯
I wanted to say was…
我要說的是…
I…
我…
Yes?
怎樣？
"I'm sorry."
很抱歉
"About today
包括今天的事也是
and everything that I did until now."
這段日子以來有很多事 我都對你感到抱歉
"It won't happen ever again. I'll treat you better from now on."
往後不會再有這種事 我真的會好好對你
That's what I wanted
我想要跟你說的
to say.
就是這些
But you only have three months to live? How's that possible?
可是你卻說你快死了？只剩三個月？ 這像話嗎？
How can I live without you?
沒有你，我要怎麼活下去？
How is that possible?
這怎麼有可能？
I'm so dumbfounded
我實在是不敢相信
that I don't know what to say.
不知道該說些什麼才好
Are you serious?
你是說真的嗎？
Yes, you fool.
對，你這個傻瓜
I love you, Hong Hae-in.
我愛你，洪海仁
I love you.
我愛你
Please give them a round of applause
請大家再次熱烈掌聲鼓勵
as they begin their new journey.
祝福兩位有充滿希望的開始
Please clap and cheer even louder
祝福兩位過得幸福美滿
to wish them the very best.
請大家給他們更熱烈的掌聲與歡呼
Everyone, please look at the camera!
來，請大家看鏡頭
Please laugh on the count of three.
數到三就哈哈大笑喔
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Mr. Baek, congratulations on the wedding.
新郎，恭喜你
Please say something to yourself in ten years.
請對十年後的你說句話
How are you doing, Hyun-woo from the future?
十年後的賢祐，你過得好嗎？
Don't tell me you got a divorce.
你該不會離婚了吧？
Do you have kids?
你有小孩了嗎？
One? Two?
一個？兩個？
It doesn't matter though.
不過沒有也沒關係
Because all I need is Hae-in.
因為我只要有海仁在我身邊就可以了
I hope you still remember
我只希望你到了那時候
how much you love her
也能夠記得你是有多麼愛她
even to this day.
現在才會在這裡
Don't make her cry.
不要讓她哭
Make her happy.
讓她幸福
Why must I answer that?
為什麼要講那個？
It'll be something nice to watch in the future.
以後再來看應該會很不錯
I'll be too busy with life to watch this in ten years.
為什麼十年之後要看這種東西？ 我應該會很忙
Do I have to do this?
一定要講嗎？
Dear Hae-in from the future.
十年後的海仁
I doubt you're watching this. But if you are, why are you?
雖然我認為你不會看這個 不過要是你在看，你為什麼要看？
Turn this off and get to work.
馬上關掉，去做你的事
I won't ask how you're doing since I know you'll be doing fine.
我不會問你過得好不好那種 老套的問題，我知道你一定過得很好
You'll be just as pretty, healthy,
你肯定依舊美麗又健康
and the most successful.
並且最為成功
With Hyun-woo by your side, of course.
不過當然是和白賢祐一起
QUEEN OF TEARS
《淚之女王》
But you only have three months to live? How's that possible?
你會死？只剩三個月？這像話嗎？
If you can't live without me… Do you want to die together?
如果你沒有我活不下去 要跟我一起死嗎？
I'm just happy
只要能夠不被報復
that I can escape from them safe and sound.
安全逃離那個家，我就滿足了
Put your heart and soul into loving her.
全心全意愛她到令人發毛
I'm that materialistic?
我有那麼現實嗎？
I'll be sitting here.
我想要坐近一點
-Are you okay? -They should just argue instead.
-你還好嗎？ -乾脆吵架還比較好
How can we change after years of living as strangers?
我們都像陌生人一樣好久了 事到如今，哪有辦法？
Watch out!
小心！
I thought of Hae-in now and then.
我偶爾會想起海仁
So it feels odd to meet her husband.
看到她先生，心情有點微妙
I don't even like Hong Hae-in. Why would I feel jealous?
我又不喜歡洪海仁，我怎麼會嫉妒？
Subtitle translation by: Soo-ji Kim
字幕翻譯：彭向棻